Shorjoe Bhattacharya Senior Operations Program Manager

WORK EXPERIENCE

Adani Logistics Limited

Digital Transformation Program Manager

Ahmedabad, GJ | Feb 2021 - current

- Spearheaded Logistics Control Tower Project that is running 70+ trains, and moving 7 million+ tons of cargo
- Program Managed Digital Transformation Initiative for CEO rolling out 6 new logistics operating systems to capture and feed information to control tower
- Automated reconciliation processes to close cost and revenue leakages in cost worth 730 crores annually

Adani Logistics Limited

Head Last Mile Operations

Ahmedabad, GJ | April 2020 - Feb 2021

- Led Team of 15+ dispatchers, 400 daily trucking movements across 11 states across India, with annual revenue of 100 Cr annually
- Drove performance visibility across sites by increasing execution rate from 50% to excess of 90% to ensure timely delivery to customers and meeting of train schedules
- Increased profitability of road movements from 1% when taking over department to 5% at time of departure leading to earnings of over 4 Cr per year

Adani Ports and Special Economic Zone

Resource Planning and Business Development

Mundra Port, GJ | June 2017 - May 2020

- Program Lead for engagement with STEP Logistics a startup investment of Adani Ports – Resulting in diversion of 1000's of net new containers from other ports to Adani Ports
- Product Manager for Port Optimizer A system rolled out in the largest port of India that cut empty internal trucks trips between sea terminals by 40%
- Lead Analyst for mapping cargo flow across India to improve ancillary revenue by over 50%

Wilmar International

Product Development Co-Op

Shanghai, China | Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

- On site, full semester apprentice at Wilmar International, Asia's largest agribusiness group with revenue of over \$50 billion.
- Designed a new health based food ingredient for the Chinese market (patent pending in China)

Shorjoe@gmail.com

+91 9099005666 Ahmedabad, GJ, IN <u>Linkedin</u> US Citizen /OCI Holder

SKILLS

- Product development, requirements gathering,
- User stories, testing
- Operations Management
- Budgeting
- ProgramManagement
- MS Excel/Project/Visio, Power BI, SQL
- Agile methodologies
- Pre-Sales Analysis

EDUCATION

B.S. Industrial Engineering
B.S. Econometrics
Southern Methodist
University
Aug 2012 – May 2017
Dallas, TX, USA

SUMMARY

Program manager with 5+ years of experience running technology programs, experience in product design, operations management, and pre-sales. Spearheaded logistics control tower program that is operating system for moving 360,000 containers more than 7 million tons annually.